<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Homes on Nitish Srivastava</title>
    <link>https://nitish2112.github.io/home/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Homes on Nitish Srivastava</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2016 Nitish Srivastava</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://nitish2112.github.io/home/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://nitish2112.github.io/home/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nitish2112.github.io/home/about/</guid>
      <description>Biography I am a software engineer in the edge TPU group at Google. I completed my Ph.D. at Cornell University where I developed domain-specific language, T2S-Tensor, to productively generate high-performance accelerators for dense tensor computations and a domain-specific hardware, Tensaurus, to accelerate mixed sparse-dense tensor computations. I was advised by Prof. David Albonesi and Prof. Zhiru Zhang. Before coming to Cornell, I obtained my Bachelor of Technology degree in Electrical Engineering from Indian Institute of Technology, Kanpur, where I was awarded with the President&amp;rsquo;s Gold Medal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>https://nitish2112.github.io/home/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nitish2112.github.io/home/publications/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talks</title>
      <link>https://nitish2112.github.io/home/talks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nitish2112.github.io/home/talks/</guid>
      <description>MatRaptor: A Sparse-Sparse Matrix Multiplication Accelerator Based on Row-Wise Product Sparse-sparse matrix multiplication (SpGEMM) is a computation kernel widely used in numerous application domains. MatRaptor, a novel SpGEMM accelerator, is high performance and highly resource efficient. Unlike conventional methods using inner or outer product as the meta operation for matrix multiplication, our approach is based on row-wise product, which offers a better tradeoff in terms of data reuse and on-chip memory requirements, and achieves higher performance for large sparse matrices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recent News</title>
      <link>https://nitish2112.github.io/home/industry/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nitish2112.github.io/home/industry/</guid>
      <description>Inaccel announces record-breaking speed on facial detection test using an FPGA cluster InAccel, a world-pioneer in the domain of FPGA-based accelerators, has released an integrated framework that allows to utilize the power of an FPGA cluster for face detection, see news Specifically, InAccel has presented a demo in which a cluster of 8 FPGAs are used to provide up to 1700 fps (supporting up to 56 cameras with 30 fps in a single server).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Posts</title>
      <link>https://nitish2112.github.io/home/posts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nitish2112.github.io/home/posts/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://nitish2112.github.io/home/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nitish2112.github.io/home/projects/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching</title>
      <link>https://nitish2112.github.io/home/teaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nitish2112.github.io/home/teaching/</guid>
      <description>I have been TA for following courses at Cornell University:
 CS3420: Embedded Systems  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://nitish2112.github.io/home/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nitish2112.github.io/home/contact/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>